you guys can you believe this whole
thing is equal to one let's verify it
first I want to leave this alone so
let's make a copy of it down here and
let's handle it one fraction at a time
let's do this one first in order to get
rid of the radical in the denominator
I'm going to multiply top and bottom by
the conjugate all we do is copy these
two terms but change the plus to a minus
on top is just going to be 1 times this
so we're just going to be left with root
1 minus root 2. and the square root of 1
is equal to one and on bottom we can use
the notes for the difference of two
squares so we know that root a plus root
c times root a minus root C is just a
minus C and we can see here that a is
one and C is two so on bottom we're
going to have one minus two and we can
clean up one minus 2 to give us negative
one to get rid of this negative 1 in the
denominator we can multiply top bottom
by negative one this negative is going
to distribute to both of these making it
a negative one and a positive root 2.
and on bottom negative 1 times negative
1 is just positive one and since we have
one in the denominator we don't need it
anymore all of this right here
simplified into negative 1 plus root two
in fact we don't even need this red
stuff this first fraction simplified
into negative 1 plus root 2. so now
let's focus on this next fraction we're
going to do the same thing multiply top
and bottom by the conjugate on top we're
just going to have the root 2 minus root
3. and the bottom we're going to use
these notes again but in this case a is
2 and C is 3. so on bottom we're going
to have the a minus C which is 2 minus
three and then 2 minus 3 is equal to
negative one and we can divide both
these top terms by negative one making
this first one negative and the second
one positive so we have negative root 2
plus root three if we can smush these
together and that takes care of this
second fraction now let's focus on this
third one multiply top and bottom by the
conjugate the top is just going to be
root 3 minus root four and the bottom
we're going to use these notes one more
time where a is equal to 3 and C is
equal to four so a minus C is going to
be 3 minus four three minus four is
equal to negative one these terms
divided by negative one will make the
first one negative and the second one
positive we don't need the one anymore
and we can smush this together so now we
have this expression right here this
positive root 2 and negative root 2 can
cancel each other out and this positive
root 3 and negative root 3 can also
cancel each other out and the square
root of 4 is equal to two let's bring
this down here negative one plus two is
equal to positive one that means that
this original crazy expression is equal
to one now we could put a box around it
how exciting